Sagar Jaysing Pawar (1) Featured

BE, Java Developer with 3.9 years of experience.



Current Location: Mumbai Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Pune, Navi Mumbai Notice Period: 1 Month

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Computers]

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Application Development, Requirement Gathering, Software Design, Software

Testing, Software Coding, MVC, Struts

Frameworks, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery, AJAX, MySQL, Maven, Jenkins, Eclipse, STS, Deployment

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

2.9 years of experience in Full Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) includes requirements gathering, analysis, design, testing, coding, integrations, implementation, enhancements.

Have working knowledge of Core JAVA, J2EE, Struts and Hibernate with strong debugging skills.

Knowledge in spring and Web Services.

Experience in web application design using MVC, and Struts Frameworks.

Experience in client side Technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX.

Basic knowledge of RDBMS concepts with MySQL and MSSQL.

Excellent communication and interpersonal skills and involved in client interactions for requirement gathering and status

Experience in using Tortoise SVN version control tool & basic knowledge of Github.

Actively involved in R&D and POC, Discussion, Estimation and Delivery of requirements.

Involved in functional requirement analysis & related discussions due to excellent knowledge of the product.

Work Experience

Nexstep Infotech (Expenzing) as Software Engineer

Dec 2017 to Jul 2020

Developed new Customer Requirements.

Impact Analysis of new development.

Have integrated the Accounting, Payment reverse and HRMS with client system.

Peer Code Review.

On-Time delivery of work.

WAR Creation & Deployment.

Coding/Development of New Enhancements for Product and Project.

Production bug analysis and bug fixing.

Adya Enterprise as Process Engineer

Feb 2016 to Mar 2017

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Chemical) from Thadomal Shahani Engineering College, Bandra in 2015

PG: PG Diploma (Computers) from SQUAD Infotech Pvt. Ltd. Vashi in 2017

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Diploma

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Java, JavaScript			
JSP, Servlet, JDBC, Struts 1.1			
Hibernate 3.0, REST, Spring.			
POI, Quartz, Log4j, Mail Api.			
Apache Tomcat 7.0			
Jboss6.0, Jboss7.0			
MySql5.0, MS SQL 2008, Oracle 10g			
SVN, GIT			
Eclipse,STS			
Maven, Jenkins(continuous Integration)			
Eclipse, SQLYOG Client, Postman			
Tortoise SVN, MS Office			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Hindi	Expert			
Marathi	Expert			
English	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: Expense Controller & Travel Management (Product)

Client: IDFC Bank

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2017 - Jul 2020 Role: Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Core Java, Jsp, Java Script, Ajax, Struts, Hibernate, Mysql, Oracle

Role Description: 1.Developed new Customer Requirement?s.

2.Impact Analysis of new development.

3. Have integrated the Accounting, Payment reverse and HRMS with client system.

4. Peer Code Review.

5. Coding/Development of New Enhancements for Product and Project.

Project Details: EMS (renamed from TnE- Travel and Expense Management) helps the companies to manage expenses in various areas like Business Expense Management & Travel Management. The Business Expense and Travel system will

help Employees put up Claims related to the Business and Travel Expenses incurred by them including expenses incurred on regular basis like Mobile Expenses.

Job Type: Permanent

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

Category: General